Step Inside
The International Space Station
Columbus Laboratory Module
Europe’s contribution to the station offers a variety
of research facilities for the crew
to study materials science, fluid physics, and
the effects of microgravity on the body.
Japanese Experiment Module “Kibo”
Japan contributes life science research,
external demonstrations,
satellite deployments, a robotic arm,
and other key research facilities.
Science on all sides
Multipurpose research shelving units called
EXPRESS Racks support as many as 100 experiments at a time.
Harmony Module
Known as Node 2, Harmony connects international
science labs and houses four crew quarters
for astronauts to sleep and
work in while aboard station.
Destiny Laboratory Module
Station’s main U.S. laboratory, Destiny
enables a wide variety of experiments
that improve life on Earth and help prepare
for future missions to the Moon and Mars.
Unity Module
Known as Node 1, Unity provides living and working space
for crew members, including a kitchen and dining area.
Cupola
The space station’s “window to the world” offers
views of Earth from seven different windows.
Quest Airlock
Astronauts have conducted many
spacewalks throughout station’s life
to upgrade capabilities and install platforms
to study Earth and the universe.
Enhanced Spaceflight Diet
Scientists are studying how dietary improvements
affect immune function, the gut microbiome,
and nutritional status to improve
human adaptation to spaceflight.
Pressurized Mating Adapters
This Pressurized Mating Adapter (PMA 1)
connects the U.S. and Russian segments
of the space station and
also serves as a storage area.
Zarya Module
The first space station component launched,
Zarya orbited Earth alone for 16 days
before space shuttle Endeavour
arrived to install the Unity modul
Zvezda Service Module
The first fully Russian contribution
to the space station,
Zvezda was an early cornerstone
of human habitation aboard the station.
Nauka Multipurpose Laboratory Module
The Multipurpose Laboratory Module is named
Nauka, the Russian word for “science,”
and serves as a science facility,
docking port, and spacewalk airlock.
Poisk Research Module
Poisk provides a docking port for the crewed Soyuz
spacecraft and the Progress cargo spacecraft,
and it also is a place for cosmonauts
to prepare for spacewalks.
International Partnership
A collaboration of five space agencies
from 15 countries operate the space station.
Environmental Control
and Life Support System
The station’s life support system recycles
essential resources like air and water,
and can recover up to 98% of the
water used in the U.S. segment.
Crew Earth Observations
Astronauts photograph the Earth from their unique vantage
point to document human impacts,
record weather patterns, and monitor
major natural events like hurricanes.
Research Results
Since November 2000, more than 4,000 investigations
have been conducted aboard the space station,
generating more than 4,500 research papers
and countless benefits to humanity.
The Ride to Station
SpaceX’s Dragon can carry crew
and cargo to the space station
and is one of several spacecraft currently
supporting station operations.
Producer:
Nicole Rose
Editor:
Devin Boldt
Nicole Rose
Videographer:
Samantha Cristoforetti
Kjell Lindgren
Nicole Mann
Oleg Novitsky
Image Credit:
ESA (European Space Agency)
JAXA (Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency)
NASA
Roscosmos
Music Courtesy of
Universal Production Music
Learn more at
nasa.gov/iss-science